Now that's it for classes.
-: الآن هذا كل شيء للصفوف.
We learned about classes themselves.
تعلمنا عن الفصول نفسها.
We learned about their properties,
لقد تعلمنا عن خصائصها ،
the axis modifiers,
ومعدلات المحور ، والخاصة
private for internal axis,
بالمحور الداخلي ، والمحمية
protected for internal axis also in inherited classes,
للمحور الداخلي أيضًا في الفئات الموروثة ،
and public for axis from everywhere.
وعامًا للمحور من كل مكان.
We also learned about methods which we can add.
تعلمنا أيضًا عن الطرق التي يمكننا إضافتها.
About static methods and properties.
حول الأساليب الثابتة والخصائص.
About abstract methods
حول الأساليب المجردة والفئات
and abstract classes, which is important
المجردة ، وهو أمر مهم عندما نتحدث
when we talk about another important concept,
عن مفهوم مهم آخر ، وهو الميراث الذي يمكننا
the inheritance which we can use.
استخدامه.
Here, we are inheriting from 'Department' with the
هنا ، نحن نرث من "القسم" بالكلمة الرئيسية
'extends' keyword.
"يمتد".
This allows us to share functionalities,
يتيح لنا ذلك مشاركة الوظائف والخصائص
properties and methods,
والأساليب ، من فئة
from the 'Department' class with this inheriting class
"القسم" مع هذه الفئة الموروثة وإضافة
and add our own functionalities
وظائفنا الخاصة أو تجاوز
or override existing functionalities.
الوظائف الحالية.
Either because we have to override
إما لأننا يجب أن نتجاوز كما
as in the case of 'describe' which is a abstract method.
في حالة "وصف" وهي طريقة مجردة.
Or because we want to override, like in the case of
أو لأننا نريد التجاوز ، كما في حالة "addEmployee"
'addEmployee' here in the Accounting Department.
هنا في قسم المحاسبة.
That's not a abstract method in the base class,
هذه ليست طريقة مجردة في الفئة الأساسية ، لكن
but of course we still can override it if we want to.
بالطبع لا يزال بإمكاننا تجاوزها إذا أردنا ذلك.
We also learned about the singleton pattern
تعلمنا أيضًا عن النمط الفردي و "المنشئات
and 'private constructors' which can also be
الخاصة" والتي يمكن أن تكون مفيدة أيضًا في
useful sometimes.
بعض الأحيان.
And then for overall, you now hopefully have a good idea of
وبعد ذلك بشكل عام ، نأمل الآن أن تكون لديك فكرة جيدة
classes and what you can do with them in TypeScript.
عن الفئات وما يمكنك فعله بها في TypeScript.
In general, of course, you would need to know what classes
بشكل عام ، بالطبع ، ستحتاج إلى معرفة
and objects, and also a bit what prototypes are about
الفئات والكائنات ، وكذلك بعض الشيء عن النماذج
in Vanilla JavaScript because that's generally not
الأولية في Vanilla JavaScript لأن هذا ليس شيئًا مقدمًا
something introduced by TypeScript,
بواسطة TypeScript ، ولكن بالطبع
but of course something TypeScript is related to
شيء مرتبط بـ TypeScript لأن TypeScript
because TypeScript builds up on these default
يبني على هذه ميزات JavaScript الافتراضية ،
JavaScript features, and adds it's own magic
ويضيف سحرها الخاص فوق هذه الميزات.